<resources>
    <string name="app_name">activity_Information</string>

    <string name="register">Register</string>
    <string name="email_address">Email Address</string>
    <string name="full_name">Full Name</string>
    <string name="username">Username</string>
    <string name="password">Password</string>

    <string name="already_Account">Already have an Account? <b>Sign in</b></string>
    <string name="program_name">Focus</string>
    <string name="welcome_text">Welcome!</string>
    <string name="welcomeBack_text">Welcome Back!</string>

    <string name="LogIn">Log In</string>
    <string name="signIn">Sign In</string>
    <string name="signUp">Sign Up</string>

    <string name="signIn_now">Sign In now</string>

    <string name="logo_white">logo_focus</string>
    <string name="half_globe">half_globe</string>
    <string name="createAcc">Create your new account</string>
    <string name="logPrev_acc">Login to your account</string>
    <string name="connect_with_us">Connect with Us</string>
    <string name="don_t_have_an_account_sign_up">Don’t have an account? <b>Sign Up</b></string>
    <string name="hey_there">Hey there!</string>
    <string name="birthdate">Birthdate</string>
    <string name="country">Country</string>
    <string name="select_your_gender">Select your Gender</string>
    <string name="female">Female</string>
    <string name="male">Male</string>
    <string name="others_gender">Others</string>
    <string name="mm_dd_yy">mm-dd-yy</string>
    <string name="phone_number">Phone Number</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="gender">Gender</string>
    <string name="state">State</string>
    <string name="interests">Interests</string>
    <string name="province">Province</string>
    <string name="log_out">Log Out</string>
    <string name="loading">Loading...</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello, World!</string>
    <string name="forget_password">Forget Password?</string>
    <string name="forgot_password">Forgot Password</string>

    <string name="user_profile">User Profile</string>
    <string name="hello">Hello World</string>
    <string name="calculator">Calculator</string>
    <string name="signout">Sign Out</string>
    <string name="user_information">User Information</string>
    <string name="back">Back</string>
    <string name="ac">AC</string>
    <string name="_0">0</string>
    <string name="_1">1</string>
    <string name="_2">2</string>
    <string name="_3">3</string>
    <string name="_add">+</string>
    <string name="_period">.</string>
    <string name="_equals">=</string>
    <string name="_4">4</string>
    <string name="_5">5</string>
    <string name="_6">6</string>
    <string name="_minus">-</string>
    <string name="del">Del</string>
    <string name="_percent">%</string>
    <string name="_divide">/</string>
    <string name="_7">7</string>
    <string name="_8">8</string>
    <string name="_9">9</string>
    <string name="backhome">backHome</string>
    <string name="_multiply">x</string>
    <string name="myName">Sherivic Dimagculang</string>
    <string name="close_parenthesis">)</string>
    <string name="open_parenthesis">(</string>
    <string name="bluetooth">Bluetooth</string>
    <string name="study">Study</string>

    <string name="intro">Infrared (IR) communication is a wireless technology that uses
        infrared light waves to transmit data over short distances. Operating on a
        spectrum just below visible light, IR communication is invisible to the human
        eye but can carry data through modulated light pulses. It has been widely
        used in consumer electronics, particularly in remote controls for televisions,
        audio systems, air conditioners, and other household devices.</string>

    <string name="IR_fundamentals">The basic components of an IR communication system include:\n\n
    <b>•IR Transmitter</b>: The transmitter is responsible for converting electronic signals into infrared light pulses. It typically consists of an infrared LED and a driver circuit that modulates the LED\'s intensity to encode the data.\n\n
     <b>•IR Channel </b>: The IR channel is the medium through which the infrared light travels, which is typically free space.\n\n
     <b>•IR Receiver </b>: The receiver is responsible for detecting the infrared light pulses and converting them back into electronic signals. It typically includes a photodetector, such as a photodiode or phototransistor, and supporting circuitry for signal amplification and demodulation.\n\n
     <b>•Modulation and Demodulation</b>: Modulation is the process of encoding the data onto the infrared light carrier, while demodulation is the process of decoding the data from the received infrared signal.\n\n
    The most common modulation techniques used in IR communication are:\n
    - On-Off Keying (OOK): The simplest form of modulation, where the LED is turned on and off to represent binary data.\n
    - Pulse-Position Modulation (PPM): The data is encoded by the position of the pulse within a fixed time slot.\n
    - Pulse-Width Modulation (PWM): The data is encoded by the width of the pulse within a fixed time slot.
</string>
    <string name="IRTransmitter"> <b>IR Transmitter</b>: The transmitter is responsible for converting electronic signals into infrared light pulses. It typically consists of an infrared LED and a driver circuit that modulates the LED\'s intensity to encode the data.</string>
    <string name="IRChannel"><b>IR Channel</b>: The IR channel is the medium through which the infrared light travels, which is typically free space.</string>
    <string name="IRReceiver"><b>IR Receiver</b>: The receiver is responsible for detecting the infrared light pulses and converting them back into electronic signals. It typically includes a photodetector, such as a photodiode or phototransistor, and supporting circuitry for signal amplification and demodulation.</string>
    <string name="IRModulation"><b>Modulation and Demodulation</b>: Modulation is the process of encoding the data onto the infrared light carrier, while demodulation is the process of decoding the data from the received infrared signal.</string>
    <string name="IRWorks"><b>1. Transmission Process</b>\n\n The transmission process in infrared communication begins with digital data in the form of binary 1s and 0s that need to be transmitted. This digital information undergoes conversion into electrical signals through specialized circuitry.
        Once converted, these electrical signals are then modulated using various techniques, with pulse width modulation being one of the most common methods. This modulation helps in making the signal more suitable for transmission and less susceptible to interference.
        The final stage of transmission involves an infrared LED, which acts as the primary transmission component. This LED converts the modulated electrical signals into pulses of infrared light,
        effectively transforming the original digital data into a form that can be transmitted through space.\n\n
        <b>2. Propagation</b>\n\n During the propagation phase, the infrared light signals travel through the transmission medium, which is typically air, although other mediums can also be used. These light signals can travel in two primary ways: either directly in a straight line between the transmitter and receiver (line of sight), or by bouncing off various surfaces such as walls and ceilings (diffuse transmission). The effective range and quality of this propagation
        depend on several critical factors. The power output of the transmitter plays a crucial role in determining how far the signal can travel.
        Environmental conditions, such as ambient light and atmospheric interference, can significantly affect signal quality. The sensitivity of the receiver determines how well weak signals can be detected,
        and physical obstacles in the transmission path can block or degrade the signal, affecting overall communication quality.\n\n
        <b>3. Reception Process</b>\n\n The reception process begins with a photodetector, typically either an IR photodiode or phototransistor,
        which is specifically designed to detect incoming infrared light signals. When these light signals reach the photodetector,
        it performs the crucial task of converting them back into electrical signals, essentially reversing the initial transmission process.
        However, these initial electrical signals are usually very weak and require amplification through specialized circuits to bring them to usable levels.
        Once amplified, the signals undergo demodulation, a process that extracts the original digital information from the modulated carrier signal.
        Finally, the receiving device processes this recovered digital data, interpreting it according to the specific communication protocol being used.
        This complete reception process ensures that the original digital information is accurately recovered and can be used by the receiving device
        as intended.</string>

    <string name="IRAdvantagesandLimitation"><b>Advantages of Infrared Communication:</b>\n\n •Low cost and simple implementation\n •Immunity to
        electromagnetic interference\n •Highly directional, providing secure point-to-point communication\n •No licensing requirements for use\n\n
        <b>Limitations of Infrared Communication:</b>\n\n  •Line-of-sight requirement, limiting range and obstructing obstacles\n •Low data rates
        compared to other wireless technologies\n •Interference from ambient light sources\n •Limited penetration through certain materials</string>

    <string name="IRApplications">Infrared communication has a wide range of applications due to its ability to transmit data wirelessly over short distances. Some of its primary applications are:  \n\n
        <b>1. Remote Controls:</b> Infrared remote controls are ubiquitous in consumer electronics, such as TVs, air conditioners, and home entertainment systems.\n
        <b>2. Wireless Data Transfer:</b> IR communication is used for short-range, line-of-sight data transfer between devices, such as file sharing between smartphones, laptops, and printers.\n
        <b>3. Industrial Automation:</b> IR communication is used in industrial environments for wireless control and monitoring of equipment, as well as for data transmission between devices.\n
        <b>4. Optical Communication:</b> Infrared light is used in fiber-optic communication systems for long-distance data transmission.\n
        <b>5. Medical Applications:</b> IR communication is used in medical devices, such as wireless patient monitoring systems and remote control of medical equipment.\n
        <b>6. Security and Access Control:</b> IR communication is used in security systems for remote control and access management.</string>

    <string name="IRProtocols">Infrared (IR) communication is widely used for short-range wireless communication, particularly in remote controls, data exchange, and point-to-point communication. Several protocols and standards ensure that devices can effectively communicate over IR, each defining specific communication parameters like data rates, modulation schemes, and frame structures. \n\n
        <b>IrDA (Infrared Data Association):</b> IrDA is a widely recognized standard for short-range, point-to-point IR communication.It defines specifications across the physical, link, and application layers, ensuring smooth data exchange between devices.This is often used in mobile phones, laptops, and printers for data transfer in close proximity.\n\n
        <b>IRMP (Infrared Multi-Protocol):</b> IRMP is an open-source protocol supporting a variety of IR remote control codes.It is particularly valuable in applications requiring support for multiple remote control types across different brands and devices.\n\n
        <b>SIRCS (Sony Infrared Remote Control System):</b> SIRCS is a proprietary protocol developed by Sony, tailored for Sony\'s range of remote control devices. It is known for its simple and reliable design, it allows Sony devices to communicate seamlessly over IR.\n\n
        <b>NEC (Nippon Electric Company) Protocol:</b> The NEC protocol is one of the most commonly used standards in consumer electronics for IR remote controls. Its popularity stems from its efficiency and compatibility with a wide range of devices, making it prevalent in television and audio equipment remote controls.\n\n
        Each protocol provides a unique combination of data rate, modulation scheme, and frame structure, which helps standardize IR communication across compatible devices and ensures interoperability between them. These IR protocols have become integral to various applications, particularly in consumer electronics and point-to-point data transfer setups.</string>
    <string name="tv_BluetoothIntro">
        Bluetooth is a wireless technology standard designed for exchanging data between fixed and
        mobile devices over short distances using UHF radio waves in the ISM bands, from 2.402 GHz to
        2.480 GHz. Developed by Ericsson in 1994, Bluetooth was originally conceived as a
        wireless alternative to RS-232 data cables. The name \"Bluetooth\" comes
        from Harald Bluetooth, a 10th-century Danish king known for uniting Danish
        tribes into a single kingdom. Similarly, Bluetooth technology was intended
        to unite different communication protocols into one universal standard.</string>
    <string name="tv_BTIntroTitle"><b>Introduction to Bluetooth Technology</b></string>
    <string name="tv_BTTimeline1"><b>Version 1.0 and 1.0B (1999)</b>\nInitial commercial release with data transfer rates up to 721 kbps and a range of approximately 10 meters, but faced issues with interoperability and connection reliability.</string>
    <string name="tv_BTTimeline2"><b>Version 2.0 + EDR (2004)</b>\nEnhanced Data Rate (EDR) increased data speeds to 3 Mbps and reduced power consumption by 50%.</string>
    <string name="tv_BTTimeline3"><b>Version 4.0 + LE (2010)</b>\nIntroduced Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE) for ultra-low power consumption and extended range up to 100 meters.</string>
    <string name="tv_BTTimeline4"><b>Version 5.0 (2016)</b>\nDoubled the speed (2 Mbps) and quadrupled the range (up to 400 meters), making it ideal for IoT applications.</string>


    <string name="BTConnection"> <b>1. Device Discovery (Inquiry)</b>\nThe connection process starts with device discovery, where the source device scans for nearby Bluetooth-enabled devices within range. During this inquiry phase, the device detects and lists available devices by collecting information like the device name, class, and address. This creates a list of discoverable devices, allowing the user to choose the intended recipient for the file transfer.\n\n
        <b>2. Service Discovery</b>\nAfter selecting the recipient device, the source device proceeds with service discovery. This step ensures that the target device supports file transfer services. The source device checks for the availability of the OBEX (Object Exchange) protocol, which is commonly used in Bluetooth file transfers. It also identifies compatible profiles, such as the File Transfer Profile (FTP) or Object Push Profile (OPP), which define the device\'s capability to send or receive files.\n\n
        <b>3. Pairing Process</b>\nBefore data transfer can take place, the devices must establish a secure connection through the pairing process. This involves exchanging security information, such as verifying a PIN code if required. Upon successful verification, the devices generate a unique link key to create an encrypted, secure link for file transfer. This pairing process ensures that the communication channel is secure, preventing unauthorized access during the transfer of files.</string>

    <string name="BTBasicConceptsIntro"> Bluetooth technology has evolved significantly since its 1999 inception, improving in speed, range, and power efficiency.\nThe major Bluetooth versions:</string>
    <string name="BTProtocol"><b>OBEX (Object Exchange) Protocol</b>\nOBEX is a session-based protocol similar in structure to HTTP, specifically designed to facilitate object-oriented data exchange over Bluetooth.
        It manages the formatting and packaging of objects for smooth transmission, handles data segmentation, and controls the flow of data
        during the transfer process. Additionally, OBEX provides error-checking mechanisms to ensure data integrity and reliability,
        making it a reliable choice for Bluetooth file transfers.\n\n<b>Supported Profiles:</b></string>

    <string name="tv_BTDeviceIdentification"><b>Bluetooth Device Address (BD_ADDR)</b>\nThe Bluetooth Device Address (BD_ADDR) is a 48-bit unique address assigned to every Bluetooth device. This address serves as the Bluetooth equivalent of a MAC (Media Access Control) address, providing a standardized way to uniquely identify Bluetooth devices. The BD_ADDR is programmed into the device\'s Bluetooth radio module during the manufacturing process and remains fixed throughout the device\'s lifetime.\n\n<b>Bluetooth Device Class</b>\nBluetooth devices are categorized based on their intended functionality, as defined by the Bluetooth specification. These device classes include phones, computers, audio devices, and various other types of Bluetooth-enabled products. By recognizing the device class, an inquiring device can gain high-level information about the type of Bluetooth device it has discovered, which can be useful for many applications.\n\n<b>Bluetooth Device Name</b>\nIn addition to the unique BD_ADDR, Bluetooth devices can also be identified by their user-friendly device name. While the device name is not a unique identifier like the BD_ADDR, it can still provide useful information to help recognize and differentiate between Bluetooth devices, especially when multiple devices of the same class are present.\n\n<b>Clock Offset</b>\nThe clock offset is a parameter that can be obtained during the Bluetooth device discovery process. This offset represents the timing difference between the internal clocks of the inquiring device and the discovered device. The clock offset can be used to help synchronize communication between the devices and maintain a consistent connection.</string>
    <string name="BTDeviceClass">Understanding the different classes of Bluetooth devices and the services they offer is crucial for accurately identifying and categorizing Bluetooth devices in wireless data transfer.\n\n<b>Bluetooth Device Classes</b>\nThe Bluetooth specification categorizes devices into various classes based on their intended functionality and capabilities, enabling better organization and identification of Bluetooth devices. Common device classes include smartphones, laptops, audio devices (such as headphones and speakers), wearables, and IoT sensors, each designed to support specific Bluetooth services that define their data exchange and communication capabilities. Recognizing a device’s class provides valuable insights into its type and potential applications, facilitating efficient management and use of Bluetooth-enabled devices.\n\n<b>Bluetooth Device Capabilities</b>\nBluetooth devices are further distinguished by specific capabilities, such as transmission power and the supported Bluetooth version. Transmission power impacts the effective range and signal strength, with higher-powered devices, like those using Bluetooth 5.0, being detectable at greater distances. The Bluetooth version also influences a device’s feature set, performance, and compatibility with other Bluetooth devices; newer versions bring improvements like higher data rates, extended range, and better power efficiency. Analyzing these capabilities helps categorize Bluetooth devices, infer their potential use cases, and assess their compatibility with other Bluetooth-enabled systems.</string>
    <string name="tv_BTProcess1"><b>Inquiry Mode</b>\nBluetooth devices that want to discover other nearby devices enter an \"inquiry\" mode. In this mode, the device starts broadcasting inquiry messages over the Bluetooth radio spectrum</string>
    <string name="tv_BTProcess2"><b>Inquiry Scan</b>\nNearby Bluetooth devices that are in discoverable mode (have their discoverability turned on) will be listening for these inquiry messages. When they receive an inquiry, they respond with information about themselves.</string>
    <string name="tv_BTProcess3"><b>Device Response</b>\nThe responding devices send back a packet containing their Bluetooth Device Address (BD_ADDR), which is a unique 48-bit identifier, as well as other information like device class and clock offset.</string>
    <string name="tv_BTProcess4"><b>Device Identification</b>\nThe inquiring device collects the responses from nearby Bluetooth devices and can use the BD_ADDR to uniquely identify each discovered device.</string>

    <string-array name="philippines_provinces">
        <item>Abra</item>
        <item>Agusan del Norte</item>
        <item>Agusan del Sur</item>
        <item>Aklan</item>
        <item>Albay</item>
        <item>Antique</item>
        <item>Apayao</item>
        <item>Aurora</item>
        <item>Basilan</item>
        <item>Bataan</item>
        <item>Batanes</item>
        <item>Batangas</item>
        <item>Beaunan</item>
        <item>Biliran</item>
        <item>Bohol</item>
        <item>Bukidnon</item>
        <item>Bukidnon</item>
        <item>Bulacan</item>
        <item>Cagayan</item>
        <item>Camarines Norte</item>
        <item>Camarines Sur</item>
        <item>Camiguin</item>
        <item>Capiz</item>
        <item>Cavite</item>
        <item>Cebu</item>
        <item>Compostela Valley</item>
        <item>Cotabato</item>
        <item>Davao de Oro</item>
        <item>Davao del Norte</item>
        <item>Davao del Sur</item>
        <item>Davao Occidental</item>
        <item>Davao Oriental</item>
        <item>Dinagat Islands</item>
        <item>Eastern Samar</item>
        <item>Guimaras</item>
        <item>Ifugao</item>
        <item>Ilocos Norte</item>
        <item>Ilocos Sur</item>
        <item>Iloilo</item>
        <item>Isabela</item>
        <item>Kalinga</item>
        <item>Kalayaan</item>
        <item>La Union</item>
        <item>Laguna</item>
        <item>Lanao del Norte</item>
        <item>Lanao del Sur</item>
        <item>La Union</item>
        <item>Las Piñas</item>
        <item>Layag-Layag</item>
        <item>Marinduque</item>
        <item>Masbate</item>
        <item>Metro Manila</item>
        <item>Misamis Occidental</item>
        <item>Misamis Oriental</item>
        <item>Mountain Province</item>
        <item>Negros Occidental</item>
        <item>Negros Oriental</item>
        <item>North Cotabato</item>
        <item>Northern Samar</item>
        <item>Nueva Ecija</item>
        <item>Nueva Vizcaya</item>
        <item>Occidental Mindoro</item>
        <item>Oriental Mindoro</item>
        <item>Palawan</item>
        <item>Pampanga</item>
        <item>Pangasinan</item>
        <item>Rizal</item>
        <item>Romblon</item>
        <item>Roxas</item>
        <item>Samar</item>
        <item>San Juan</item>
        <item>Saranggani</item>
        <item>Siquijor</item>
        <item>Sorsogon</item>
        <item>South Cotabato</item>
        <item>Southern Leyte</item>
        <item>Sultan Kudarat</item>
        <item>Sulu</item>
        <item>Tarlac</item>
        <item>Taguig</item>
        <item>Tambon</item>
        <item>Tanauan</item>
        <item>Western Samar</item>
        <item>Zambales</item>
        <item>Zamboanga del Norte</item>
        <item>Zamboanga del Sur</item>
        <item>Zamboanga Sibugay</item>
    </string-array>


</resources>